

CONTACT

Phone 0916.356.243

Email longk15t@gmail.com

Website www.linkedin.com/in/longk15t/

Long Tran

Senior Test Engineer

SUMMARY

Senior software QA tester with full system development lifecycle experience, including designing, developing and implementing test plans, test cases and test processes. Familiar with testing web-based, Android, iOS, MAC OS, Linux applications.

Developed, implemented, and maintained the user acceptance and full regression test cases/scripts/scenarios to ensure user-level and back-end qualities for Windows applications. Develop Continuous Integration system, apply DevOps process for rapidly delivering products with reliable and high quality.

SKILLS

Hard skills

- Testing Methodologies
- Test Plans, Cases & Processes
- Functional Requirements
- Scripting & Documentation
- Regression & Negative Testing
- Performance/Load/Stress Testing
- Testing Automation (UI Automation)
- Defect/Bug Tracking
- Continuous Integration (Jenkins)
- Python, HTML, VBScript, Groovy, Shell, Cmd
- AWS service (EC2, CloudFront)

Soft skills

- Problem solving
- Collaboration
- Interpersonal skills

WORK EXPERIENCES

Personify Inc. Senior Test Engineer (2016-04 to 2018-04)

- Automation testing for Windows applications (Presenter, ChromaCam) by UI Automation in Python.
- Develops, integrates Jenkins with SCM, make every pull request/release/tag get verified/tested by unit testing, regression testing to detect errors at early phases.
- Setups 4 machines (3 Windows, 1 Linux) to work as slave nodes of

- Jenkins, speed up verification/testing process.
- Creates Test plan, test process, conduct testing for Teleporter application
- Windows version using HTC Vive and Teleporter Android version.
- Saves about 400\$ monthly billing for company after downgrade instance type of AWS EC2 which was used as Wowza server (for media streaming).

Personify Inc. Test Engineer (2013-02 to 2016-04):

- Performs basic testing duties with Windows/MAC OS X/Android/iOS/Web applications, create bug reports on Trello/JIRA for programmers investigate and repair.
- Collaborates with other QA technicians to ensure major/critical bugs were not presented before publish release.
- Test Plan, Test Cases, Test Reports documentation.
- Finalizes report template to devs, product owner.
- Handles customer requests/issues/requirements from Desk.com, remoting to customer's machine to debug issue/bugs.
- Performs load testing Wowza server on AWS EC2 by Python (Ubuntu) to identify threshold of concurrent connections server can handle.
- Self improve, research and learn useful information/tools to improve working quality.
- Support team member, other teams to solve problems.

EDUCATION

B.Sc., Information Technology, Van Lang University (2009-2013)

Team leader of graduation project (MHS – speed up register process of patient in hospital, written in C#)

CERTIFICATIONS AND AWARDS

- Subject certificates in CMU (Student ID: T093686)
 http://strategic.isri.cmu.edu/elearning/val/home/index.jsp
- Nominated for Test Team Star 2015-2016 Award
- Certificate of Excellent 2016-2017

ADDITIONAL ACTIVITIES

- Joined Python Vietnam Skype group
- Member of Quora in Testing, Networking, Command Prompt subject
- Joined Jenkins Users Google Group
- Joining an English class to get IELTS certification
- Planning to get ISTQB certification